# **Software Developer | Web Developer**

A passionate **Software Developer** with the hands-on practical knowledge of development as well as testing in software industry with agile methodology and great debugging capabilities. I envision successful and like to be part of an organization which promotes me to use my software engineering background knowledge and experience to develop and test the code.

## **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

- **3+ years of experience** in industry as a **Web Developer** with the strategy to handle front-end, back- end and debugging the code.
- Experience in all the activities of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), different team projects with good project implementation experience, team skills, troubleshooting, presentation abilities and issue resolution capabilities.
- Possess **good experience in Design, Coding, Testing and Implementation of projects** executing on multiple platforms such as Web and mobile.
- Technical proficiency in a high paced production environment capable of being an effective team player
  with exceptional planning and execution skills coupled with a systematic approach and quick adaptability.
- Familiar with **Web technologies** like VUE, JSON, XML, JavaScript, J-Query, AJAX and HTML5.
- **Knowledge of languages** like Java, Python, Database, PHP, JavaScript, C# and extensive knowledge of **IDE** and **Tools** like Eclipse, Vs-Code, PHPStrom3, Git, Postman,Swagger, Jira, Slack and Source-Tree.
- experience of Data driven testing, **Cross browser testing**, Parallel and Sequential testing, Database testing using Selenium Web driver.
- Basic Knowledge of networking concepts like OSI Model, TCP/IP, & Network Protocols.
- Strong skills to involve in the communication with Development team as well as knows how to work in Agile Methodology.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

• BiotracelT Corp. Dec 2019 - Present UI/UX Software Developer

- Developed the **administrative portal**, control modules and **data presentation** of the application by using **Vue is** as a single page front-end application.
- Collaborates with the team of developers and designers to create an innovative **user interface** of the application which quantify the **acute** and **chronic pain** in pets and human body.
- Assisted in **conducting** tests of product launches to ensure that **software** runs smoothly and meets clients requirements.
- Developed the reusable **components and libraries** of vuetify framework to a standard and compatible which makes it quick and easy to maintain the code in the future.
- Source, select and organize information for inclusion and design of the appearance, layout, and workflow of software medical device application.
- Develop and configure the **essential files** of project and describe each environment in file as per the project perspective.
- Building up and **enhancing integration** within existing system. Furthermore, carrying out tasks related to deploy life cycle.
- Developed the entire front-end by using **vuetify component JavaScript framework** and ensure that the **project security** is maintained and the software modifications as per project requirement.

- **Junior Web Developer**
- Designed and developed the website of Conservative Party of Canada with using WordPress as a front-end and PHP as a back-end language.
- Learned how to use **Amazon Web Service** to store code repository in cloud and deployment of code in different environment.
- Developed new plugins and installed for the website to make user interface best as per project perspective.
- Learned how to maintain the data services and contribute to increase existing data services API.
- Developed the database of the campaign and used to pull data from database to get the list of the people who donate money.
- Worked in the team to accomplish the requirement of the project as per party requirement and learn work under pressure.
- Provided Weekly status updates showing the progress of the Manual testing effort and open issues to be resolved in JIRA Tracking Tool.
- Maintain the back-end code and database as well to make sure the website is working smoothly.

# • Zyelon Computech

May 2014 - Aug 2015

### **Junior Front-End Developer**

- Built up and enhanced integration of UI design within the existing system and carried out tasks related to web development life cycle.
- Worked in the group to fulfill the project requirements as per project and kept up the consistency in designing, layout, built with CSS & HTML, bootstrap, and JavaScript.
- Learn how to code from the existing material as per client and project necessity under the senior developer by using different framework.
- Familiar with the web-application tools like bit-bucket, buddy-works, PostgreSQL, Postman and light amount of Json.
- Implementing the functionality of JavaScript, jQuery and PHP. Additionally, created the logos, banners website.
- Learn how to work in the team and how to troubleshoot the errors and bugs from the code.
- Studied how to use the Code-igniter framework by using PHP, HTML, & CSS.

# **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Computer Programmer

May 2016 – Dec 2018

Algonquin College of Arts and Technology, Ottawa, Canada

• Bachelor's in Computer Applications

Jun 2011 - April 2014

Saurasthra University, Rajkot, India

### **INTERNSHIPS**

### • J2 Global & Cloud Service- Intern Software Developer

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Learned deployment process by using tool octopus and puppet chef from **DevOps** manager in multiple environments at a same time by automating in C#.
- I-Sight Customer Expression- Intern Software Tester

Jan 2018 - April 2018

• Actively participated in all QA and testing activities in various environment as well as tested application compatibility on different browsers (Chrome, IE, Fire Fox, Safari).

# **REFERENCES**

Available upon request